<chapter id="c01intro">
	<title>Introduction</title>

	<section id="c01osss">
		<title>&openser; SIP Server</title>
		<para>
			July 28, 2008, the project name changed from OPENSER to KAMAILIO.
			In June 2005, &openser; was born as a
			split from SIP Express Router project of FhG FOKUS Institute, Berlin, Germany.
			The newly created project was aiming to create an open development environment to 
			build robust and scalable open source SIP server.
		</para>
		<para>
			The website of the project is <ulink url="http://wwww.kamailio.org">http://www.kamailio.org</ulink>.
			The source code is hosted on <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net">sourceforge.net</ulink> SVN
			repository.
		</para>
		<para>
			Today &openser; SIP Server is a reference implementation, featuring hundreds of VoIP services
			world wide, being developed by people around the world. It is included in official distributions
			of several Linux and BSD flavors.
		</para>
		<para>
			The number of registered developers and packagers exceeded 25. The level of contributions and the 
			amount of contributors has an important impact on the evolution of the project. The book tries
			to ease the understanding of &openser; from a developer point of view, giving the kick start
			knowledge, it does not intend to be a cookbook. Efforts to improve the documentation in the 
			sources is undertaken and make it <emphasis role="strong">doxygen</emphasis> compliant, making
			a good developer documentation out of there.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section id="c01ata">
		<title>About the authors</title>
		<para>
			<emphasis role="bold">Daniel-Constantin Mierla</emphasis> is one of the co-founders of
			&openser; SIP Server project. He is involved in VoIP and SIP since beginning of 2002,
			at FhG FOKUS Institute, Berlin, Germany, being involved as core developer in the
			SIP Express Router project. Currently he is employed by
			<ulink url="http://www.asipto.com">ASIPTO</ulink>, an &openser;-focused
			company. Daniel is an active OPENSER developer and member of management board.
		</para>
		<para>
			<emphasis role="bold">Elena-Ramona Modroiu</emphasis> is one of the co-founder of 
			&openser; SIP Server project. She got involved in VoIP and SIP while working at her
			graduation thesis within SIP Express Router project at FhG FOKUS Institute. She completed
			studies at Polytechnic University of Valencia and Siemens Germany, working now at
			<ulink url="http://www.asipto.com">ASIPTO</ulink>,
			being an active developer and member of management board of &openser;.
		</para>
		<para>
			The two authored many online tutorials about &openser; that include <emphasis>&openser;
				Core Cookbook</emphasis>, <emphasis>&openser; Transformations</emphasis>,
			<emphasis>&openser; Pseudo-variables</emphasis>, <emphasis>&openser; and Asterisk Integration</emphasis>,
			<emphasis>&openser; and FreeRADIUS</emphasis>.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section id="c01important">
		<title>Important</title>
		<para>
			This document is focusing only to &openser; specific API, has no intention to teach
			C programing for Linux and Networking. You, as a reader, should have already the
			basic knowledge of C programming.
		</para>
		<para>
			Do not contact the authors to ask about standard C functions or variables.
		</para>
		<para>
			There are many references to parts of code in the source tree. You must be familiar
			with the directory structure of &openser;. It is not our intention to explain how
			something was implemented, but how to use existing code to extend &openser; easily.
		</para>
		<para>
			The source code remains the best reference for developers. In the last time, the comments
			around the important functions in &openser; have been improved and converted to
			<emphasis role="strong">doxygen</emphasis> format. You should double-check the source
			code if the prototype of the functions presented in this document are still valid.
		</para>
		<para>
			Daily updated <emphasis role="strong">doxygen</emphasis> documentation is available at
			<ulink url="http://devel.kamailio.net/doxygen/">http://devel.openser.org/doxygen/</ulink>.
		</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
