<chapter id="c14datalump">
	<title>Data Lumps</title>
	<para>
		A topic that won't be involved very much in the development of new features, but important
		to understand as it is one of the most discussed issues related to &kamailio;.
	</para>
	<para>
		Many are surprised to discover that even they remove a header from the original SIP message,
		in the configuration file, when they test later for header existence it is still then. Why?
		Because the data lumps are behind the remove operations.
	</para>
	<para>
		The modifications to the original SIP message instructed from configuration file are not applied
		immediately. They are actually added in a list of operations to be done. Practically, changing
		the content of the SIP message from the configuration file translates in creating a diff
		(like in diff/patch tools from Unix/Linux systems) and putting it in the list. The diffs
		are applied after the configuration file is executed, before sending the SIP message further
		to the network.
	</para>
	<para>
		Note that in config of &kamailio; 3.x, you can use msg_apply_changes() exported by textopsx
		module to apply immediately the changes done to the content of the SIP message.
	</para>
	<para>
		There are two types of diff operations:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				add content - this diff command is specified by the position in the original SIP
				message and the value to be added there. The value can be a static string, or a
				special marker to be interpreted later, when required information is available. For
				the later, it is the case of Record-Route headers where it is needed to set the
				IP address of the socket that is used to send the message further. That address
				is detected just before sending through the socket.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				remove content - this diff command is specified by the position in the original SIP
				message and the length to be deleted.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>
		There are two classes of data lumps:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				message lumps - these lumps are associated to the SIP message currently processed. The
				changes incurred by these lumps are visible when the SIP message is forwarded.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				reply lumps - these lumps can be used when the processed SIP message is a request
				and you want to add content to the reply to be sent for that request. Here cannot be
				lumps that delete content as the SIP reply is to be constructed from the SIP
				request.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>
		Maybe future releases will touch deeper this subject, depending on the interest. If you want to
		investigate by yourself, start with files <emphasis role="strong">data_lump.{c,h}</emphasis> and
		<emphasis role="strong">data_lump_rpl.{c,h}</emphasis>.
	</para>
</chapter>
